DANIEL TORRES CALVO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Costa Rica

PHONE

8587-2400

EMAIL

daniel.torres.calvo@outlook.com

DATE OF BIRTH

27/04/1996

DRIVING LICENSE

B1

LINKS

LinkedIn

<u>Portfolio</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

SKILLS

Teamwork

Communication

Adaptability

Proactive

Troubleshooting

Mentoring

LANGUAGES

Spanish

• • • • •

English B2

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

HOBBIES

Movies

Reach

CrossFit

Music

Travel

PROFILE

Responsible and motivated software developer with 4+ years of experience. With knowledge about user interfaces, testing, and debugging processes. Proficient in an assortment of technologies including Java, JavaScript and excellent experience of relational databases. Able to work productively in a team in agile environments.

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Senior Analyst, Accenture

Heredia

Jun 2023 — Present

Back-end development with Spring Boot and technologies such as AWS SQS, Docker, Amazon Lambdas, Amazon S3, Jenkins, etc. Responsible of migrate existing applications to a microservices architecture with Spring Cloud. Able to work independently on high difficult tasks. Liable of assist the release management team for pushing new features to Dev, QA and Production environments.

Software Development Analyst, Accenture

Heredia

Aug 2021 — May 2023

Back-end development with Spring and technologies such as Spring Boot, Maven, JPA, GraphQL, AEM, JUnit, Mockito, etc. Responsible of the creation of new endpoints, services and resolution of problems that affect the existing integration. Develop OSGi service components to integrate with backend systems usign RESTful APIs. Work on several projects providing solutions that follows best practices with coding standards, unit testing and continuous integration.

Software Developer, SysCo Consultores

San José

Nov 2019 — Aug 2021

Full-stack development with Spring and technologies like Spring Boot, Spring Data, JSP, JavaScript, SASS and Oracle database. Gained experience building customer facing web based applications, web services RESTful and code collaboration in teams using GIT and SVN. Responsible to identify user requirements and implement solutions to new and existing projects.

EDUCATION

Licentiate's degree, Computer Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica

Feb 2021 — Present

Bachelor's degree, Systems Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica

Feb 2014 — Nov 2019